(647) 679-8032 ☑ torabian.alireza@gmail.com

Alireza Torabian

Machine Learning Researcher/Engineer

% 1997alireza.github.io 1997alireza **in** alireza-torabian

As a machine learning researcher and software engineer with a strong math background, I have been involved with different projects in various areas including deep learning, computer vision, adversarial machine learning, and natural language processing.

EXPERIENCE

Jun. 2023 - Present **Huawei Technologies** R&D software engineer Markham, Canada

· Optimizing LLVM in the high-performance BiSheng compiler.

York University Jan. 2021 - Aug. 2023

Machine learning researcher

Toronto, Canada Established a structured and formal framework for machine learning calibration.

Introduced a metric for calibration to achieve a less-biased evaluation.

Amirkabir University of Technology, NLP Lab

Jan. 2020 - Aug. 2020 NLP researcher (Github repo) Tehran, Iran

• Developed a real-time question-answering system based on a knowledge base in Python.

A sequence-tagging model based on BERT is used for named entity recognition (NER).

SVM and CNN classification models used to classify questions achieved 96% accuracy and F1-score of 92.7%.

National University of Singapore, Data Privacy and Trustworthy Machine Learning Research Lab Jul. 2019 - Sep. 2019 Computer vision researcher (Github repo)

Singapore

Oct. 2016 - Sep. 2017

2015-2020

• Developed a plugin that obscures images for increased privacy using adversarial attacks, with a 35% success rate.

Performed facial recognition attack on FaceNet and face detection attack on SSD MobileNet V1 using PGD.

• Used image augmentations to attack black-box models increased success rate by 1.5x.

Diaalog Jul. 2018 - Dec. 2018

Deep learning R&D intern (Clustering Github repo), (Language model Github repo) Tehran, Iran

Developed a Persian chatbot using Python Tensorflow.

Expanded dataset by clustering questions with LDA and using answers interchangeably.

LSTM Seq2Seq model with Luong-style attention mechanism is used to generate answers.

Amirkabir University of Technology, Cognitive Robotics Lab

Research assistant Tehran, Iran

Developed an autonomous exploration algorithm for robots that won 2nd place in RoboCup 2017.

Object detection task performed to detect victims using YOLO model achieved 99.7% accuracy.

EDUCATION

York University 2021-2023

M.Sc. in Computer Science, GPA: A+ Toronto, Canada

Amirkabir University of Technology (Tehran Polytechnic) Tehran, Iran

B.Sc. in Computer (Software) Engineering, GPA: 3.9/4

SKILLS

Languages Python, Java, C++, JavaScript

TensorFlow, PyTorch, OpenCV, Keras, Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, NLTK, Scipy, JAX Machine learning

Databases MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Cloud **AWS** Big Data Spark

Other Tools Git, Unix shell, Jupyter

Math ML Theory, Stats & Prob, Signal Proc., Stochastic Processes, Convex Optimization

OTHER PROJECTS

Alternative Actor and Co-Star Suggestion Using a Graph Autoencoder Model

• Applied graph autoencoder to actor network using Keras in Python, achieving 99.46% accuracy in reconstructing the graph.

• An alternative actor is found by searching the latent space using a K-d tree.

• A co-star is suggested according to the predicted weights from the autoencoder model.

Jul. 2019 **Optimization Problems**

· Optimized unconstrained and constrained convex problems using line search, trust region, and log barrier.

Github repo

Apr. 2021

Github repo